Good morning!
おっはよーん
It's 8:15 on November 5th!
１１月５日　８時１５分
Ms. Akane Tsunemori's Psycho-Pass
Hue this morning is powder blue!
けさの常守朱さんのサイコパス色相はパウダーブルー
Have a wonderful day
with that healthy mind of yours!
健康な精神で素晴らしい一日を楽しんでね
Ahh... I messed up...
やっちゃった
My head is overflowing with thoughts
I can't allow anyone to know about
I've strayed into a world void of even mistakes
It's being rubbed in so deep it's hard to believe
This "world" that holds
only what the eye can see
Can I flush out the truth?
Plastic Tac Tic,
no one can go crazy anymore
You, too, are in a plastic beautiful world
In a world with too much beauty,
for some reason I can't see the light
My bursting heart is an eternal reflection
Secret remains for you
Don't expose these false colors and futures
fake's plastic world
keep it secret motion
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 翼叔   校对:西西   后期:时末
I'm not on the day shift today... right?
You're meeting up with Ms. Yuki
Funahara and Ms. Kaori Minase
今日って日勤じゃないよね
at Akebonobashi Station at 1100.
１１時から船原ゆきさま 水無瀬佳織さまと曙橋駅で待ち合わせ
At 14:30, you start second shift
duty at the Public Safety Bureau.
１４時３０分より公安局で第二当直勤務でーす
Oh, that's right...
あ～　そっか
今日のお部屋はどうします
What's your room preference today?
ヴィクトール·オルタで ホテル·タッセル
Victor Horta's Hotel Tassel.
はーい　ライブラリ参照しまーす
Okay! I'll use the library as reference!
#02: Those Capable
Your dietary intake yesterday
was a total of 2200 kilocalories.
「昨日の食事摂取量は合計２，２００キロカロリー」
The proper amount for today's
breakfast is 240 kilocalories.
「今日の朝ご飯は２４０キロカロリーが適正でーす」
２００キロカロリー  テイストはチャイニーズで
I'll have a 200-kilocalorie
Chinese-flavored breakfast.
Certainly!
「かしこまりました」
It was my very first day on the job...
配属初日でさ
Why'd I have to? Gimme a break...
何でよ
もう…
Today's weather is cloudy
followed by sunny skies.
今日の天気は曇り後晴れ
The chance of precipitation is 0 percent.
降水確率は０％
The anticipated group stress
in Shinjuku Ward is Level 3.
新宿区で予測される集団ストレスはレベル３
I recommend you take a supplement
to prevent mental contamination.
心理汚染の予防サプリがお勧めです
I guess this is okay.
こんなとこかな
Well then, see you later.
じゃあ　行ってくるね
Take care!
お気を付けて
So... you messed up, huh?
で…
やらかしちゃったわけだ
Yeah... though since
I work for the MWPSB,
公安局の仕事なんで
I can't give you the details.
詳しいことは言えないけど
I don't know much about these things,
よく分かんないけどさ
but what you did wasn't in
violation of your duties, right?
それはあんたの役職に許されていることなんでしょ
Well, yeah.
まあね
Then, you don't
have to worry about it, right?
じゃあ　気に病むことないじゃない
Besides, your Psycho-Pass
isn't that clouded, either.
サイコパスだってそんなに曇ってないし
Isn't it actually that you're
not really bothered by it?
案外本当は平気なんじゃないの
Oh, don't be mean!
I couldn't sleep at all last night.
え～　そんな
ゆうべは全然眠れなかったのに
To think that the Hue Check
shows a clear color for you
それだけ悩んでおいて
色相チェックはクリアカラーなんだもんね　朱は
even when you were so distressed...
You don't give yourself
much psychological care,
感情ケアなんてほとんどやってないくせに
and yet, you're such a mental beauty.
すごい　メンタル美人
How can you stay so healthy?
あんたって 何でそんなに健康でいられるの
Well... I wonder if I'm thick-skinned...
まあその…　鈍感なのかな
God is really unfair.
神様ってホント不公平
Yep.
そうそう
I-In any case... it's not that
I doubt the Sibyl System,
で…でもさ　シビュラシステムを疑うわけじゃないけど
but I wonder if a career at the
Public Safety Bureau is really for me.
公安局のキャリアなんて 私に向いてるのかな
Argh! That's a problem you're lucky to have!
カア～　ぜいたくな悩み
I know you're ditzy, but still,
I can't believe you'd say that!
天然でそういうこと 言うかな～まったく
To start with, it was indicated
that you have an aptitude for jobs
だいたいさ　朱ってば
経済省や科学技術省の適性だって出てたのに
at the Ministry of Economy
and the Ministry of Technology,
and yet, you rejected them all and
picked the Public Safety Bureau, right?
それ全部蹴って公安局選んだんでしょ
I could only get C rankings.
私なんてＣ判定しかもらえなかったのにね
What's the problem?
You're good at blue-collar work.
いいじゃん　あんた体動かす仕事は得意なんだから
I'm a systems engineer. I'm always
having trouble with stiff shoulders.
私なんてＳＥよ
もう　肩凝ってしょうがないんだから
Akane, you were an honor student
who scored 700 points in the last exam.
朱はさ　最終考査でポイント７００たたき出した優等生じゃない
Any job should be a piece
of cake for you, right?
どんな仕事だって チョチョイのチョイでしょ
Sorry. We teased you too much.
ごめんね ちょっとからかい過ぎた
But I think you're
capable of pulling off that job.
でもね　朱ならきっとやり通せる仕事だと思うよ
It's not just because of
the aptitude the System indicated.
それはシステムが出した適性だけじゃない
My intuition as your friend says so, too.
友人としての直感
"What needs to be done is
done by those capable of doing it.
「成しうる者が為すべきを為す」
Such is the grace bestowed
upon mankind by Sibyl."
「これこそシビュラが人類にもたらした恩寵である」
Just kidding.
なんちってね
Excuse me! Is Analyst
Shion Karanomori here?
すみません
分析官の唐之杜志恩さんはこちらに
Yeah, that's me. Who are you?
はいはい
どちらさま
I'm Akane Tsunemori. I've been
assigned to the CID as of yesterday!
昨日付けで刑事課に配属になりました　常守朱です
Oh! You're the new Inspector
who shot Shinya, aren't you?!
ああ　慎也君を撃った新任監視官って あなたね
Wow... You're a lot cuter than I thought.
へえ～　思ってたよりずっとカワイイ子
That cute face of yours hides
how daring you can be, though.
顔に似合わず 思い切ったことするもんね
What happened? Did Shinya grab
your butt or something?
何があったの
慎也君にお尻でも触られた
No. Well... I was told I should come
to you to find out how Mr. Kogami is doing.
いえ　その
狡噛さんの容体 ここに来れば分かるって聞いて
Oh, that.
ああ　それね
While I do have a physician's license,
can you believe the government would
いくら医師免許持ってるからって
分析室に健康管理まで任せるお役所って　どう思う
actually delegate employee health care
to the Analysis Lab just because of that?
Sure, I'm a latent criminal, too.
そりゃ　私も潜在犯ですけど
But that doesn't mean
they can just slave drive me
だからって　いくらでも便利にこき使っていいって法はないでしょ
as much as they want, right?
R-Right...
Let's see... Akane, was it?
えっと あなた朱ちゃん…だっけ
If you're an Inspector, that means you're
on the fast track at the MWPSB, right?
監視官なら 公安局の出世コースでしょ
Hurry up and become a high-ranking
official so you can reform the system.
さっさと偉くなっちゃって組織改革してちょうだいよ
You can start by furnishing a swimming
pool and a bar lounge at the CID.
まずは 刑事課備え付けのプールとバーラウンジをこしらえるところから
I'm counting on you!
お願い
Uhm, well... how's
Mr. Kogami's treatment going?
いや　そのですね
狡噛さんの治療って
Oh, that's right.
あっ　そうね
Well, you got a solid
direct hit on his spinal cord,
まあ　脊髄にいい感じに直撃かましてくれたからね
so he isn't in good shape yet.
Things like standing and talking are still...
まだ本調子ってわけにはいかないわ
立ったり　しゃべったりはちょっとね
Joining him in bed,
of course, isn't possible, either.
もちろん　ベッドのお供も無理
If you just want to peek in
on him, though, that'd be okay.
顔だけでも見ていきたいっていうんなら
面会ぐらい大丈夫だけど
What do you wanna do?
どうする
W-Well, I don't want to bother him, then.
いえ　それなら別に
If he rests today,
the aftereffects should go away.
今日一日安静にしてれば後遺症も抜けるわよ
Come back tomorrow morning.
またあしたの朝にでもいらっしゃい
Okay.
はい
Hm?
Uhm...
あの
Hm?
Excuse me, are there any other tablets?
すみません
タブレットって他にあります
Enforcer Kogami is
using the spare equipment.
備品の予備は狡噛執行官が使用中でーす
But, uhm... Mr. Kogami is...
でも　その…狡噛さんは…
...undergoing treatment
after being shot by the Paralyzer.
パラライザーで撃たれて治療中でーす
Ow! Ouch...
痛え…
Here...
これ
Use this.
使って
O-Okay.
はっ　はい
Sorry for getting in late.
悪ぃ悪ぃ　遅くなって
ってあれ 今日の宿直ってお嬢ちゃん
Oh? You're on duty tonight, young lady?
Ah, yes.
あっ　はい
It must be tough after
what happened yesterday.
昨日の今日で大変だね
Well, let's hope that it'll
be a peaceful day today and...
まあ 平和な一日になるよう祈って
This is an elevated
Area Stress Level warning!
エリアストレス　上昇警報
Inside Iko Gryce Hill in Adachi Ward,
足立区 伊興グライスヒル内部にて
a Psycho-Pass above the
regulation value has been detected.
規定値超過サイコパスを計測
Inspector on duty, please go straight
to the site with Enforcers immediately.
当直監視官は執行官を伴い
直ちに現場へ直行してください
Just when we were talking
about having a peaceful day...
言ってるそばからそれかよ
Well, our shift just ended, so... good luck.
まあ　俺らはシフト明けっすから
頑張って
Would you like me to cover for Kogami?
狡噛の穴　私が埋めます？
Well, that won't be necessary.
いや　何　それには及ばんさ
Now, let's get going, Ms. Inspector.
さっ　出動だぜ　監視官殿
What?!
モール内の出入り口は
Drones have been watching
the entrances to the mall
since the warning was triggered.
警報直後から ドローンが監視してる
They haven't caught anyone.
そっちに引っ掛かった獲物はなし
In other words, the very person who's
raising the Area Stress is still in the mall.
つまり　ここのエリアストレスを高めてる張本人は
まだモールの中にいる
Are we going to use Dominators?
ドミネーターを使うんですか
We'll have them delivered
to us as a precaution,
用心のために運ばせはするが…
but we probably won't have to use them.
まあ　抜くまでのことにはなるまいよ
Well then, let's go, shall we?
そんじゃまあ　行こうかね
Is this uncomfortable for you?
落ち着かねえか？
Your generation is used to
playing with holo-suits on, right?
お嬢ちゃんぐらいの年ならホロスーツで遊ぶのなんて慣れっこだろ
I feel a little uncomfortable
with my whole body being an Avatar.
全身アバターに成りきるってのはちょっと…
It's okay, so let me see.
大丈夫
Oh, stop it.
あ～やめてってちょっと
I won't stop it.
やめないよ
Oh, that guy is the one. On the right,
he's hiding behind the front column.
あ～あれだ
右　手前の柱の陰
But... how can you tell
without even using a scanner?
そんな…スキャナーも使わずにどうして
A beast can sniff
out another beast's smell.
ケダモノはケダモノのにおいを嗅ぎ当てる
失礼しまーす！
Excuse me. Could we please
measure your Psycho-Pass?
サイコパス測定にご協力お願いできますか
Whoa... It's cloudy.
あらら　濁ってますね
緊急セラピーを要するものと判断します
My assessment is that
you require emergency therapy.
ご同行願いますね
Please come with me.
What? Why? I haven't done anything yet...
えっ　そんな…
俺はまだ何も…
To think that you really
can identify latent criminals...
本当に潜在犯の見分けがつくなんて…
You'll intuitively know at first glance
when someone's up to no good.
良からぬことを考えてるやつは
一目見ただけでピンとくるものさ
Committing a crime or cracking down on one...
罪を犯すか　取り締まるか
Either way, they're talents
that deal with criminal behavior.
どっちにしても犯罪に関わる才能であることに違いない
だから俺なんかの犯罪係数もどえらい数値になっちまうのさ
That's why my Crime Coefficient
shows a crazy number.
Because of that, I'm now treated as
a hunting dog who takes on dirty jobs.
おかげで今じゃ汚れ仕事を承る猟犬の扱いだ
I was... useless.
私　何の役にも立ってなかった
No, you were quite helpful.
いや～大助かりだぜ
Enforcers can't walk around outside
without an accompanying Inspector.
監視官同伴じゃなければ 執行官は外を出歩けねえんだから
But that's...
でも　それって…
Like I said...
だからな…
After you bring Enforcers to the site,
all you need to do is watch them
執行官を現場まで連れてきて
あとはサボったり逃げ出したり
so that they won't slack off,
run away, or cause society trouble.
世間さまにご迷惑がないようにしっかり見張る
That's all you need to do.
お嬢ちゃんの仕事はそれだけで十分なんだ
In other words, you're telling
me not to do anything, right?
それってつまり　何も手出しをするなってことですよね
ご一緒していいっすか？監視官殿
Can I join you, Ms. Inspector?
Sure.
どうぞ
I thought you were already off duty today.
今日はもう非番なんじゃ…
俺ら執行官は捕らわれの身なんだぜ？
We, Enforcers, are prisoners, you know.
Even when we're off duty,
there's nowhere else we can go
オフだって刑事課フロアと宿舎の他には行き場所なんかねえの
besides the CID floor and our quarters.
Well, sorry about earlier.
や～　昼間はごめんね
I just got carried away.
俺もついついはしゃいじゃってさ
As you can see, all the women
who work here are scary, so...
なんせここにいる女ときたらおっかねえやつばっかりだし
I'm so glad that a cute girl
like you joined the CID, Akane.
朱ちゃんみたいなカワイイ子が来てくれて
すっげえうれしいっつうか…
Oh, can I call you Akane?
あっ　「朱ちゃん」って呼んでいい
Yeah, sure.
別にいいよ
At any rate, MWPSB Inspector?
What a crazy place you chose to work for.
しっかしまあ 公安局監視官なんて
またとんでもない就職したもんだね
Why here?
何でまた？
Do you think I'm not suited for it?
向いてない…かな？
昨日のあれを見たかぎりじゃね
After what happened yesterday,
anyone would probably think that way.
誰だってそう思うんじゃない？
Sibyl's Judgment of my job aptitude
シビュラ判定の職能適性
exceeded the MWPSB's
employment standards, so...
公安局の採用基準にパスできたから
That's the thing I don't get.
そこんとこ不思議なんだけどさ
If you passed the MWPSB's standards,
公安局の基準を通ったんなら
you must've gotten a good
ranking for other places too, right?
もっと他の適性もいい判定もらえてたんでしょ？
Couldn't you pick a different job?
別の仕事だって選べたんじゃね？
Yeah.
うん…
I got an A ranking for all thirteen ministries
and agencies, and six companies.
私ね　１３省庁６公司全部Ａ判定出たんだ
What?! S-Seriously?
えっ！？マジ？
Yeah. But...
うん…でもね
...for all the other jobs, there were
at least one or two people besides me
他の仕事はどれも同じ判定をもらった子が
that got the same ranking.
私以外にも１人か２人はいたの
I was the only one who
got an A ranking for the MWPSB.
公安局のＡ判定が出たのは私だけだった
There were more than 500
students and I was the only one.
５００人以上いた学生の中でただ一人私だけ
So I thought that there must be some
work that only I could do at the MWPSB.
だから公安局にはね
私にしかできない仕事がきっとあるって思ってた
If I went there,
I thought I could find my real life...
そこに行けば本当の私の人生が…
I thought I should be able to find
out why I was born here and now!
この世界に生まれてきた意味が見つかるはずだって…
Do you think I'm wrong?
私の考え方間違ってるかな？
I don't know. What makes you think
that someone like me would know?
分かんねえよ
俺なんかに分かるわけねえじゃん
You could've become anything.
あんたは何にでもなれた
どんな人生を選ぶことだってできた
You could've chosen any kind of life.
You even agonized over it, right?
それで悩みさえしたんだろ？
That's incredible. You're just like those
old people before Sibyl was created.
すげえよな　まるでシビュラができる前のジジババみてえだ
Nowadays, the Sibyl System reads your talent
今じゃシビュラシステムがそいつの才能を読み取って
and tells you the way of living
that will bring you the most happiness.
一番幸せになれる生き方を教えてくれるってのに
And yet, you're talking about your
real life? The reason you were born?
ホントの人生？生まれてきた意味？
I never even thought there were
people who stressed over things like that!
そんなもんで悩むやつがいるなんて考えもしなかったよ
I was flagged in a Psycho-Pass
test when I was five.
俺なんて５歳でサイコパス検診にはじかれて以来
I've been a latent criminal ever since.
ずーっと潜在犯だぜ
No possibility for rehabilitation through
treatment. That's why I'm here now.
治療更生の見込み　ゼロ
だから今俺はここにいる
Becoming one of the MWPSB's hunting
dogs and taking on assassination jobs
一生隔離施設で過ごすより公安局の猟犬になって
is better than spending my
entire life in an isolation facility...
殺し屋稼業を引き受ける方がましだから
That was the only choice I had, so...
俺にはそれしかなかったからさ
I wasn't going to be mean to you or anything,
俺　別にあんたに意地悪するつもりはなかったんだけどさ
気が変わったわ
but I changed my mind. So I'll ask you again.
だからあらためて聞いてやる
Why did you become an Inspector?
あんた　何で監視官なんかになったんだ
I'm very sorry!
すみませんでした
It's rare to see an Inspector
who would apologize to an Enforcer.
執行官に謝る監視官は珍しい
I guess you're angry, right?
やっぱり　怒ってますか？
That was your decision.
I have no right to complain.
あれがあんたの判断だった
俺が文句を言える筋合いじゃない
Was my decision wrong?
私の判断間違ってたんでしょうか？
Did I just stand in everyone's way
and put them in danger?
ただチームの足を引っ張って
みんなを危険にさらしただけだったんでしょうか？
もう長いこと執行官をやっている
I've been an Enforcer for a long time.
The hunting dogs' behavior of
following orders to take down prey
迷うことなく　疑うことなく
with neither hesitation nor
doubt is engrained in my hands.
命じられたままに獲物を仕留める猟犬の習性が
俺の手には染みついちまってる
Obeying what that gun said,
I've shot many latent criminals.
あの銃の言いなりになって
何人もの潜在犯を撃ってきた
It was for the best for this society.
それがこの社会のためになると
I accepted such convenient
logic without questioning it,
小奇麗な理屈をうのみにして
and at some point,
I even stopped thinking about it.
いつの間にか考えることさえなくなった
I even forgot to look back and
see what I was doing.
自分がやっていることが何なのか顧みることさえ忘れていた
It's foolish.
バカな話だ
デカってのは誰かを狩り取る仕事じゃなくて
Being a detective isn't
about bringing someone down...
誰かを守る仕事だったはずなのにな
...rather, it should be about protecting someone.
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん…
You decided what was right on your own.
あんたは何が正しいかを自分で判断した
You were able to
put justice before your duty.
役目より正義を優先できた
Under a boss like that, I may be able
to work as a detective, not just a dog.
そういう上司の下なら
俺はただの犬ではなくデカとして働けるかもしれない
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
It's also rare to see an Inspector
who would thank an Enforcer.
執行官に礼を言う監視官も珍しい
If you had more time to think about it calmly,
もっと落ち着いて考える暇があったら
you would've tried not to shoot her, too, right?
狡噛さんだって彼女を撃とうとはしなかったですよね
I don't know.
どうだかな
I didn't hesitate at the time.
I thought I'd die if I hesitated.
あのとき俺は迷わなかった
迷えば死ぬと思っていた
I thought, "I don't want
to die in a place like this.
こんなところで終わりたくない
I cannot die here no matter what!"
絶対に　死ぬわけにはいかない
That one thought consumed me.
それだけで頭がいっぱいだった
I have unfinished business to take care of.
俺にはやり残したことがある
There's something I have
to settle no matter what!
どうあっても　始末をつけなきゃならない役目が…
Mr. Kogami!
狡噛さん…
So, you're saying that you
made the right decision at the time?
つまり　あの場における判断に間違いはなかったと…
Is that your conclusion, Inspector Tsunemori?
それが君の結論か？常守監視官
Yes. The rise of her
Crime Coefficient was temporary.
はい　彼女の犯罪係数上昇は一過性のものでした
In fact, the therapy she's receiving after
being taken into custody is going well,
事実　保護された後のセラピーも経過は良好で
and her Psycho-Pass is recovering.
サイコパスは回復に向かっています
Kogami, is there anything you want to say?
狡噛　何か言いたいことは？
No. Inspector Tsunemori fulfilled her duty.
ない
常守監視官は義務を果たした
That's all.
それだけだ
Looks like the fairy tale died a moment ago
In a hospital ward made of bricks,
I found it hard to sing
Red moon, come out on this foggy night
Now look at me, don't avert your gaze
I was born behind black iron bars
Wish for payback for the evil done
As you wish, I'll give you your justice
Before you destroy and get destroyed
Pay karma's price, and let's go together
Monster without a name
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.